Oh, we had 400
million yesterday.
So, 400 million
domestic and um
still going still
tracking out of the
dark. Let's go.
Wow,
it's beautiful.
Amazing. This is
incredible.
This is beautiful.
어. 아. 오.
감독님하고 우리 멧돼 두 분이
오셨어요.
>> 아이고
땡큐
>> 감독님
be with예
pleas예
>> 아 역시 그 감독님을 우선 네네
>> 좋습니다. 자 제가 바로 소개를
드리도록 하겠습니다. 우리 영화
오디세이의 장대한 여정을 함께한 어
두 분입니다. 크리스토퍼 놀란
감독님과 우리 배우 몇
데이먼씨입니다. 예. 반갑습니다.
>> 일단 좀 우리 많은 시청자 여러분께
또 인사를 좀 부탁드리겠습니다.
감독님. Hello.
>> 아 저야말로 진짜 너무 기쁘고
영광입니다. 예. 우리 또 예.
멧이먼 씨도 좀 부탁드리겠습니다.
인사를.헬. Hello. Weve
had such a wonderful
time and had the
most wonderful
welcome here in
Korea and we're
incredbly happy to
be here and be here
with this film. 사실 그
데이머 씨는 이게 이제 10년 만에
한국 방문인데 오랜만에 이렇게 한국에
다시 오셨는데 좀 어떠셨는지
wonderful would come
back
[음악]
>> 아 그리고 또 야구장에도 가셨잖아요.
그것도 굉장히 좀 화제가 됐었어요.
넷데이머니 오늘도 매웠습니다. 저도
방금 소식을 듣고 깜짝 놀랐는데 합성
아닙니다.
>> 어네 [웃음]
>> 스세지 감독의 명장이죠.이 이 공
갑치가
어 할리우드 데스타의 사인볼 와
부러운데요
[음악]
>> 아
>> 아니 그 어쨌든 아 전 세계 영화
팬들이 기대하려온 대작입니다.
오디세이이 개봉하자마자 69개국 박스
오피스 정상을 지금 어 찍고 드디어
한국에 개봉을 하게 되는데이 영화
소개를 좀 해 주시죠. 네.
Yeah, I mean the
Odyssey is uh based
on a 3000-year-old
poem that's kind of
the foundation of
western literature.
But none of that's
important. What's
important is it's
one of the great
adventure stories.
Uh it's a very
exciting story of
love and loss and uh
revenge uh war. It
it has all these
incredible elements.
[음악]
And I really really
uh wanted to make a
filment. I'm really
uh excited to to
bring it to Korean
audiences. We made
[음악] the film for
people who know
nothing about the
original the
mythology.
음.
개봉된에 [음악] 많은 공개된
곳에서는 재밌다라는 후기가
어마어마합니다.
어 오디세이는 어떻게 구상을 하게 된
작품인지 또 한번 궁금해서 한번
여쭤보고 싶네요. Think when
that was a more
successful than we
had hed
that usortunity we
could make a film
that maybe we
wouldn't have got to
make otherwise. And
I'd been struck by
the fact that that
the Odyssey, even
though it is this
incredibly important
story uh to to the
[음악] West, uh it had
never been told as a
modern film and as a
filmmaker, you're
looking for
something that that
you haven't done
before and you're
also looking to
bring something to
the audience that
perhaps they haven't
haven't seen before.
So the Odyssey with
all of its uh
adventure and
fantastical
elements, I mean uh
it just presented
[음악] an irresistible
opportunity to make
a film on the
grandest scale
possible and travel
the world uh with a
[음악] with a really
tremendous group of
people uh and try
and create a world
and a sense of
escapism for the
audience for a few
hours and hopefully
see some
그러니까요.
이번 촬영이 이제 영화 일곱편을
동시에 찍은 것처럼 촬영이 힘들었다
이런 소문이 굉장히 좀 찾아옵니다.
지금 그 멧이에머씨도 지금 예 살짝
좀 예 웃으셨는데
이번 저 감독님이 캐스팅할 때 고생
좀 할 거라고 좀 미리 좀 얘기를
하셨나요? 어땠나요? 감독님 좀 그런
얘기 안 하셨어요?
>> [웃음]
>> Yeah. And I said I
know I know I kind
of brushed him off
made so many and
saidered
[웃음]
>> 아 이미 이미 얘기를 하셨구나. 아,
그냥 힘들게 아니고 진짜 힘들 거야.
[웃음]
Beating sun
and from, "Yeah,
this this really is
a hard film.
>> [웃음]
>> But it's the
Odyssey. And the
thing about the
Odyssey, it is this
grand story uh that
nobody wants to hear
that [음악] we made a
film with the oddy
and it was easy and
it was nothing and
you know we shot it
over weekends
really like [음악]
it's a grand that
deses grand.
>> 야, 근데 또 감독님 얘기드니까
설득이 된다. 아니,이 대서사시의이
이야기가 쉬우면 그게 또 말이
되느냐? 그니까 납득이 됩니다. 예.
예. 납득이 돼요. 아니 그 저
감독님 영화가 이제 그 어 배우분들
입장에서는 힘들 수밖에 없는게 이게
이제 다들 아시겠지만 CG를 안
쓰기로 또 굉장히 좀 유명하신데
오디세이도 이제 산 바다 동굴까지
>> [음악]
>> 로케이션 촬영을 이제 했다고 얘기를
들었습니다. 이게 좀 실제적으로
촬영을 해보시니까 좀 어떠셨는지
>> 아 그러니까요.
add even another
layer of challenges
for for everyone.
There was no special
treatment. You know,
a lot of the days
began. We would have
to hike up [음악] a
mountain or we would
have to walk up to a
cave or and everyone
had to do it
together.
A 45 minut hike in
sandals. [웃음]
You know, we're
shooting in cave and
Greece, but nobody's
ever tried to shoot
a film up there. And
so to see the
rigging that they
did to basically
turn it into a
natural [음악] sound
stage,
I don't know any
other director who
would try it.
But the the cast was
so wonderful. The
actors were so
great. And and as
Chris said,
everybody was really
up for it. Everybody
really wanted to be
there. And you could
really feel that uh
amongst the crew and
the cast, everybody
felt lucky to be
there. And uh so it
was a very a very
driven group of of
of people who also
were experiencing
[음악] everything
together.
And there was
something really
great about sharing
that experience with
everyone. Very there
was so much
experience in that
crew but we could
all
[음악] tough thing
ever.
[웃음]
힘들다 보면 진짜 동료예가 생기고 그
안에서 끈끈함이 생기잖아요. 이게
뭔가 좀 그 그런 기운들이 다 나오지
않았나? 이게 이제 감독님은 아까
얘기하시지 않았습니까? 저도 그 예고
표현해 봤는데 그 큰 함선 예. 고게
실제 그 만들어서 거기서 이제 촬영을
하셨다는 얘기를 들었는데 이거는 진짜
연기가 아니라 생존이다. 뭐 이런
얘기를 또 조금 하시기도 하셨는데
약간 실제로 배위에서 촬영하는 그
상황 좀 어떠셨는지
green screen safe on
stage outs
and out
and so thats
>> [음악]
>> 아, 그렇습니까? 어. 아, 그렇게
감독님이 그런 것도 다 신경을
쓰셨겠죠.
>> [콧방귀]
>> Atlantic all the way
to New York and
back. So we knew
we'd be very safe.
Uh but what we had
to do was to take
Matt and his whole
crew, his his guys
and integrate them
with the real [음악]
crew of the boat. So
the crew of of the
ship was about 25
people. They all
wore costumes. [음악]
They became part of
the story. And then
all the actors
playing this as men.
They had to learn
how to row the boat.
We went out on the
boat the first time
myself [음악] and my
crew, a small crew,
my director of
photography operated
camera himself,
single camera, uh,
and they put up the
sales and they
sailed and we just
filmed it like a
documentary. So, we
were able to just
film [음악] these guys
doing all this stuff
uh for real.
J. 아, 맞아요. 그러니까
자연스럽게 아까 그 멧이먼 씨도 그
얘기를 하셨지만 진짜 몰입이 될
수밖에 없는 [음악] 실제 경험을
그대로 예, 그 이제 화면에 구현할
수 있는 [음악] 상태가 됐을 거라는
생각이 듭니다.
[음악]
이게 그 어 논란 감독님이
논란했다라는 말이 괜히 나온게 아닌게
특히 오디세이는 어 상업 영화 최초로
모든 장면을 IX 필으로 촬영을
했다고 합니다. 이게 이제 사용된
필림 길이만 640km라고
하고요.
[음악]
I'm like, does he
not like what we're
doing? Like what is
happening? [웃음]
And then I remember
it was actually [음악]
that was like no
there minutes. [웃음]
[음악]
>> 이게 사실은 이제 모든 것이 비용이지
[음악] 않습니까? 이게 비용이
만만치.
아 예. 이게 어필을 좀 고수하는
이유가 좀 있는지 한번 여쭤보고
싶네요.
Kodak 65 mm film
sees colors and
detail the way the
eye sees it. So if
what you want to do
as a filmmaker, if
you're wanting to
take the audience
there, have [음악] the
screen disappear so
that you feel like
you're there, you
feel like you're on
the boat with a
disus, you feel like
you're going into
the cave of the
cyclops with a
disus, it's the best
format to do that.
It's the best
meeting to do that
because it gives the
clearest, sharpest
image and it really
allows you to feel
what things would
smell like and taste
like feel like. And
for me that's a
great way of of
making the the story
more exciting for
the audience.
Action the camera
has to stop every 2
and minut.
[음악]
이게 참 아맥스관이 많이 없다 보니까
지금 벌써 매진이에요. 저희가 예매를
하려도 할 수가 없어. 지금 그죠?
예. 지금 다 매진이에요. 감동.
Well, it's great
that they all sold
out, but the every
other screen
benefits from the
fact that we shilm.
>> 그렇죠. 예. [웃음]
아스 필립으로 찍어서 아맥스로 보면
좋지만 그렇지 않더라도 괜찮다. 다
보실 수 있다.
[웃음]
예.
바로 그거라고. 예. 아 정말 저도
뭐 아까 얘기 드렸습니다만 아 너무
보고 싶어요. 어 배우들이 이제 가끔
이제 열심히 최설하시지만 엔진을 낼
수가 있잖아요. 예 혹시 그런 것
때문에 속으로 좀 화가 나신 적도 있
[웃음]
아. 비용이 나
>> 아 영수 좀 받으셨어요? 예노
[웃음]
>> 이렇게 긴 촬영을 마치고 가장 먼저
한 일이 뭔지 한번 여쭤봐도
되겠습니까?
prepared [음악]
champ toast the
entire crew normally
a crew would either
[음악]
do that quickly skip
that or just you
know everyone would
be ready to go home.
>> [음악]
>> Hwed [음악]
[한숨]
감독님께서는 좀 어떠셨는지
궁금합니다.
Well, he's not he's
wrapped basically
today. I was going
to say [웃음]
the film for me
isn't finished. I
mean, I say this to
the actors when I
say goodbye. I said,
"Well, I'll be
seeing you every day
in the edit for
months and months
and months." and
it's actually very
strange for me to
see, you know, when
I when I showed the
film the first time,
we haven't seen each
other for s or eight
months, but to me,
I've been seeing him
every day and
studying
every every
expression and every
every tone of voice
and and everything.
Uh so yeah, the film
the film carries on
and carries on and
uh um it's not
finished for me
until the audience
[음악] sees it. So
yes, I that's thank
you for that answer.
That's a good
answer. [음악] Yeah.
Yeah. Thank you very
much. You have so
many cameras. Thank
you so [음악] much.
Thank you so much.
Never seen so many
cameras.
H